

Ph.D. STUDENT IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AT GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

■ seongmin@gatech.edu | # https://www.seongmin.xyz | Seongmin Lee | Seongmin Lee | @ Seongmin Lee

Summary_

I'm a Ph.D. student in Computer Science at Georgia Tech, advised by Professor Polo Chau. My research aims to provide explanations and interpretations for various machine learning techniques based on visualization. I received my B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering from Seoul National University in February 2021. I have collaborated with researchers and developers of Cisco Systems, Inc. and AVAST Software.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Georgia, USA

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Seoul National University

Aug. 2021 - Present

Advisor: Prof. Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

Seoul, South Korea

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Mar. 2016 - Feb. 2021

Graduated with Summa Cum Laude. Overall GPA: 3.91/4.0, Major GPA: 3.94/4.0

Korea Science Academy of KAIST

Busan, South Korea

MATH AND SCIENCE SPECIALIZED HIGH SCHOOL

Feb. 2013 - Feb. 2016

One year early entrance, Graduated with distinction in GPA

Research Experience

Cisco Systems, Inc.

California, USA (Remote)

PHD Intern May. 2022 - Jul. 2022

Mentor: Ali Payani

· Added machine learning explanation and visualization features to RAI, a (to be) open-sourced project for responsible AI.

- Improved disentangled representation learning algorithms and visualized the results for better interpretability.
- Investigated CNNs by visualizing how the concepts in the input images affect the feature representations from the neural networks using synthetic data.

Polo Club of Data Science, Georgia Institute of Technology

Georgia, USA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Aug. 2021 - Present

Advisor: Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

- Led a project to help people assess website reliability by providing visual explanations of how each website engages in spreading false information
- Developed an interactive visualization tool to detect biases in CNN classifiers.
- Participating in a project to investigate how a concept evolves while training neural networks.

Data Mining Lab, Seoul National University

Undergraduate Research Internship and Bachelor's Thesis

Seoul, South Korea

Jan. 2020 - Feb. 2021

Advisor: Prof. U Kang

Undergraduate Research Internship

- Investigated multi-source domain adaptation under various constraints and settings.
- Resolved the limitation of BERT that the tasks with few training data are hard to fine-tune by pruning proper attention heads based on reinforcement learning.

Communication and Machine Learning Laboratory, Seoul National University

Seoul, South Korea

Sep. 2019 - Apr. 2020

Advisor: Prof. Jungwoo Lee

• Studied the problem of class imbalance and uncertainty in semantic segmentation.

Biomedical Precision Laboratory, The University of Tokyo

Tokyo, Japan

Undergraduate Research Internship

Jul. 2018 - Aug. 2018

Advisor: Dr. Keiichi Nakagawa, Dr. Ayumu Ishijima

- Collaborated with 3 students majoring in biology and physics to observe interaction between human cells and acoustic waves.
- · Constructed a microscopic motion-picture camera with sub-nano spatial/temporal resolution using optical equipments and laser.
- Processed the microscopic images using Matlab for better analysis.

JANUARY 27. 2023 SEONGMIN LEE · RÉSUMÉ

Publications

Explaining Website Reliability by Visualizing Hyperlink Connectivity

Seongmin Lee, Sadia Afroz, Haekyu Park, Zijie J. Wang, Omar Shaikh, Vibhor Sehgal, Ankit Peshin, and Duen Horng (Polo) Chau IEEE Visualization and Visual Analytics (VIS), 2022

NOVA: A Practical Method for Creating Notebook-Ready Visual Analytics

Zijie J. Wang, David Munechika, **Seongmin Lee**, and Duen Horng (Polo) Chau IEEE Visualization and Visual Analytics (VIS) Poster, 2022

VisCUIT: Visual Auditor for Bias in CNN Image Classifier

Seongmin Lee, Zijie J. Wang, Judy Hoffman, and Duen Horng Chau

Proceedings of the IEEE/CVF Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Demo Track, 2022

MisVis: Explaining Web Misinformation Connections via Visual Summary

Seongmin Lee, Sadia Afroz, Haekyu Park, Zijie J. Wang, Omar Shaikh, Vibhor Sehgal, Ankit Peshin, and Duen Horng Chau CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstracts, 2022

Multi-EPL: Accurate Multi-Source Domain Adaptation

Seongmin Lee, Hyunsik Jeon, and U Kang

PLOS ONE, 2021

AUBER: Automated BERT Regularization

Hyun Dong Lee*, **Seongmin Lee***, and U Kang (* These authors contributed equally to this work) PLOS ONE. 2021

Unsupervised Multi-Source Domain Adaptation with No Observable Source Data

Hyunsik Jeon, $\bf Seongmin\ Lee,$ and U Kang

PLOS ONE, 2021

Patent

Pruning Method for Attention Head in Transformer Neural Networks for Regularization and Apparatus Thereof

Seongmin Lee, Hyun Dong Lee, and U Kang

10-2020-0162397, 2020

Honors & Awards

The Presidential Science Scholarship

KOREA SCIENCE AID FOUNDATION

SNU Engineering Honor Society (STEM)

COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING, SNU

Voluntary Service Award

DEPARTMENT OF ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING, SNU

Talks

"MisVis: Explaining Web Misinformation Connections via Visual Summary", Georgia Tech, School of CSE Recruiting Event

"Explaining Website Reliability by Visualizing Hyperlink Connectivity", AVAST Software, Fake News Monthly Sync Up

"Multi-Source Domain Adaptation with Pseudo-labels", Seoul National University, AIIS Retreat

Nov. 2022 Spring 2022

Mar. 2016 - Dec. 2019

Mar. 2018 - Dec. 2019

Dec. 2018, Dec. 2017

Jun. 2020

Teaching

Data and Visual Analytics (CSE 6242), Graduate Teaching Assistant

Deep Learning Course for LG Chem, Lab session lecturer

Deep Learning Course for SK Hynix, Lab session lecturer

Introduction to Algorithm, SNU, Undergraduate student tutor

Introduction to Physics I, SNU, Undergraduate student tutor

Fall 2022

Jan. 2021

Nov. 2020

Fall 2020, Fall 2019

Spring 2017

Grants and Funding

Meta Research Funding (\$50k)

2022

Pls: Polo Chau

Co-authored proposal on developing novel visualization to curb and quantify misinformation consumption.

Cisco Research Funding (\$150k)

2022

PIs: Polo Chau

Co-authored proposal.

Skills

Programming C/C++, Python, Java, Verilog, HTML/CSS/Javascript

Frameworks Tensorflow, PyTorch

Languages Korean (Native), English (iBT: 109 (R28/L28/S26/W27), GRE: Verbal 163, Writing 4.5)

Extracurricular Activity _____

GTKSA (Georgia Tech Korean Student Association)

Aug. 2021 - Present

Mar. 2018 - Dec. 2019

Serving as a secretary and web administrator.

SNU Buddy Sep. 2020 - Dec. 2020

Buddy program for the international exchange students. Used to be a group leader.

SNU Engineering Honor Society (STEM)

Organized academic seminars, international round table, and mentoring programs as a vice president.

Vision Mentoring, Seoul National University

Jul. 2019

Lectured high school students on engineering (More than 700 students attended)

Dream Camp Mentoring, Seoul National University

Feb. 2019, Feb. 2018

Nov. 2017 - Oct. 2018

Educated high school students in the countryside by designing a mentoring program $\,$

Student Vice President

Elected as a vice president of the Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering, SNU

Student Reporter

Published brochures about the Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering every semester

Sep. 2017 - Feb. 2021

Talent Sharing Volunteer Camp, KOSAF

Jan. 2017, Aug. 2016

 $Conducted\ self-planned\ mentoring\ for\ elementary\ school\ students\ in\ underprivileged\ areas\ in\ Korea$